Finding Aid for Law School (University of Michigan), 1852-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-Visual Materials
  - Videocassettes
    Videocassettes contains six videos, including two of panels of minority Law School alumni discussing their experiences during and after their education, and one video of two panels of participants in the "Porn'im'ag'ery" controversy discussing the events surrounding the 1992 exhibition and its subsequent reinstallation in 1993.
    - Cook Lecture: "U.S. Foreign Policy and the Global Economy," by Professor Jeffrey Sachs, January 17, 18 and 19, 1995 (Box 118)
    - Hiring of Minority Faculty at Law Schools, by Patricia Williams and others, undated (Box 118)
    - Minority Alumni Panels, September 29, 1989
      - Room 132 (Box 118)
      - Rooms 120 and 138 (Box 118)
    - The Reinstallation of "Porn'im'ag'ery: Picturing Prostitutes," AM panel (speakers Lee Bollinger--Dean and Margerie Heinz--Director and Staff Counsel to American Civil Liberties Union Arts Censorship Project) and PM panel (speakers Roger Kimball--journalist and art critic, Joanna Frueh--professor of art at University of Nevada at Reno, and Carol Jacobson--Ann Arbor artist), October 16, 1993 (Box 118)
- Archived Law School Website
  The Website series (2002-2008, 2.05 GB; 2010- ) documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Law School. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and the student handbook), and information about admissions, degree requirements, curriculum, faculty, centers and programs, alumni and development, and the overall mission of the School. Also included is the Law Library website, which presents information on policies, procedures, resources, and the mission of the Library. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1996 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2002, 2003, 2006, and 2008. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Law School Website
    - 1996-[ONGOING]
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - May 15, 2002, .ZIP file
    - June 23, 2003, .ZIP file
    - May 19, 2006, .ZIP file
    - May 14, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the Law School, 2010-[ongoing]
Related Material
Related record groups in the Bentley Historical Library include the Law School Library, the Law School Website, the Law School Oral History Interviews, the Jeffersonian Society, the Lawyers Club, the Legal Aid Society, Michigan Club Court, Ohio Club Court, the Webster Debating Society, and the records of Joseph Sax (Collector), formerly the Michigan Environmental Protection Act of 1970.
The Bentley also holds the personal papers of deans James V. Campbell, Thomas M. Cooley, Charles A. Kent, Henry W. Rogers, Harry B. Hutchins, Henry M. Bates, E. Blythe Stason, Charles W. Joiner, and Theodore St. Antoine; and the personal papers of members of the law faculty including Ralph W. Aigler, William Warner Bishop, Jr., William Wirt Blume, Elizabeth Gaspar Brown, Alfred Conard, Harry T. Edwards, Alpheus Felch, Edwin Goddard, Levi Griffin, Paul Kauper, Victor Hugo Lane, Marcus Plant, Alan Polasky, Roy Proffitt, John Welsley Reed, Joseph Sax, Burke Shartel, Eric Stein, Edson Sunderland, Charles Walker, William Wells, and Horace Wilgus.